<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on rxOred&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://rxOred.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on rxOred&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 09:46:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rxOred.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Practical Reverse Engineering Answers</title>
      <link>https://rxOred.github.io/post/practical-re-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 09:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxOred.github.io/post/practical-re-answers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello, rxOred here, with another badly written write-up.
A years ago, i started reading practical reverse engineering book. Eventhough I was familiar with most of those concepts, that book&amp;rsquo;s exercises were pretty challenging. Aand guess what, there were no solutions to those Exercises in the book. Authors have encouraged RE community to share solutions with others using their blogs, r/reverse-egnineering etc.
At that time, i never really wanted to create a blog.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, rxOred here, with another badly written write-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A years ago, i started reading practical reverse engineering book. Eventhough I was familiar with most of those concepts,
that book&amp;rsquo;s exercises were pretty challenging.
Aand guess what, there were no solutions to those Exercises in the book. Authors have encouraged RE community to share
solutions with others using their blogs, r/reverse-egnineering etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, i never really wanted to create a blog. however while doing those challenges, i have wrote
some, not-very-detailed explainations. So, i will be sharing those stuff with yall.
This 2 part series post will provide some solutions for Exercises in chapter 1, which is about x86.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-1-page-11&#34;&gt;Chapter 1, page 11&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 bytes (32 bits). makes sense right? if you have read the whole snippet, line 5 is a,
repne scasb
intel indentifies these instructions as string operation instructions. which is perfectly fine.About scasb,
scasb/scasw/scasd instructions compare al/ax/eax with value at memory address specified in edi. rep is a prefix.
it is used for repeating same thing. So the what the whole instruction does is, it compares al (because scas&amp;rsquo;b&#39;)
with whatever value at memory address specified in edi while increasing edi by 1 until the byte is found in the
buffer or ecx == 0. so as for our answer, it is 4 bytes because since edi is an memory address, memory addresses in
x86 takes upto 4bytes :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 byte
rep stosb
this instruction is used to initialize a buffer with some value (like memset). edi should contain the address of
buffer, and since its a stos&amp;rsquo;b&#39;, which is the indication of byte, al contain the value that the buffer should be
assigned with. So from that, it is clear that ebp+c, second argument to the function is sizeof byte:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the snippet does is pretty simple, in line 1, edi is assigned with ebp+8 (first arg), which we concluded as a
memory address. next line, we can see that its saving that address in edx followed by a xor eax, eax, which clears
out eax register. In line 4, ecx is ored(did i spell that correct?) with 0xffffffff. result of this operation is,
well, 0xffffffff because anything | 1 results in a 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then we have what we discussed in 1), repe scasb. I won&amp;rsquo;t explain it again ew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So next we have some add ecx, 2, which, as anyone can guess, adds 2 to ecx. Followed by a negation. then we have a
mov  al, ebp+c, which moves our byte into al register. then edi is assigned with edx, where we saved our edi before.
Then we have what we discussed in 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what this basically does is, it compares 0 with whatever at memory address edi until 0 is found in the
buffer while decrementing ecx. then we set ecx + 2, then we negate it to get the string len, then we write [ebp-c]
to [edi] byte by byte :3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-1-page-17&#34;&gt;Chapter 1, page 17&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in this exercise we want to write a program that reads instruction pointer :3. here we go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-asm&#34; data-lang=&#34;asm&#34;&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; here we are reading address of the instruction after the call instruction.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   readeip: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;lbl&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; call lbl, this pushes address of next instruction to the stack
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;ebx&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;eax&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0x80&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; exit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
   lbl:     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;eax&lt;/span&gt;, [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;esp&lt;/span&gt;]  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; we read value at esp to eax. which is the return address.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;ret&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we have to set eip to 0xAABBCCDD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-asm&#34; data-lang=&#34;asm&#34;&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; 1. here we when we call, return address is pushed to stack
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   writeeip:   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;ebx&lt;/span&gt;,  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;eax&lt;/span&gt;,  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0x80&lt;/span&gt;

   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; 2. we then modify the value at stack to 0xAABBCCDD
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   write:      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;   [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;esp&lt;/span&gt;], &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0xAABBCCDD&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;ret&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; cause a segfault
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-asm&#34; data-lang=&#34;asm&#34;&gt;   writeeip:   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;

   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; remember, ret just pops whatever at esp to eip
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   write:      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;push&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0xAABBCCDD&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;ret&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-asm&#34; data-lang=&#34;asm&#34;&gt;   writeeip: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;jmp&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0xAABBCCDD&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;yeaup simple as that
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-asm&#34; data-lang=&#34;asm&#34;&gt;   writeeip: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;eax&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0xAABBCCDD&lt;/span&gt;
             &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;eax&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;; this is bit important. lot of malware authors use this method to access win32 APIs
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;same thing that happened to many of above snippets ?. it will crash with a seg fault. The reason is that, we are returning to
a totally unknown address.
In this case we havent pushed anything to the stack other than return address and base pointer of the prev stack frame. and when ret pops the value from stack to eip, and what we get is base of the previous
stack frame. Guess what? stack is non-executable :3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  --------------------------
           eax (y)
  --------------------------
           ecx (x)
  --------------------------
        (return addr)
  --------------------------
             ebp             &amp;lt;------- esp
  --------------------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;edx:eax will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#THE-END&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next article, we will go through the last exercise :) Until then!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compilers 101 - The front end</title>
      <link>https://rxOred.github.io/post/compilers01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 22:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxOred.github.io/post/compilers01/</guid>
      <description>Compilers This article is all about compilers.
For many people, a compiler is a mystery. for them, it is like a magical black box that takes the source file as an input and generates a binary file that can be executed.
However, the truth to be told, compilers are not wizards. In this article, we will start from the introduction to the front-end of a compiler from a reverse-engineering perspective.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;compilers&#34;&gt;Compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is all about compilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, a compiler is a mystery. for them, it is like a magical black box that takes the source file as an input and generates a binary file that can be executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the truth to be told, compilers are not wizards. In this article, we will start from the introduction to the front-end of a compiler from a reverse-engineering perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next articles will contain detailed explanations of the optimizer and the back-end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-compiler-and-how-does-it-affect-the-reverse-engineering-process&#34;&gt;What is a compiler and how does it affect the reverse engineering process.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A compiler is a very complex piece of software, and what it essentially does is, taking one representation of a program as an input and generating a representation of the same program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This input representation is usually the text file containing the source code that complies with the specifications of a specific high-level language. And the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output is usually a low-level language representation of the same program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds not that complex right? Well, this is just a high-level overview. During this process of translation between different representations, the input source will have to face many algorithms, techniques employed by the compiler to optimize the low-level representation it generates. These algorithms may add more levels of complexity on top of the original code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And may even contain code that the developer is not intended of writing. These things make it harder for someone to read the compiler-generated code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;compiler-architecture&#34;&gt;Compiler architecture.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compiler architecture mainly consists of 3 things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Front end
- Optimizer
- Back end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I this first article, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the Front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-front-end&#34;&gt;The front end.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tbh, the front is the least important out of the above 3 in a reverse engineering perspective. anyway&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this thing do? well, the front end is the place where the process of compilation begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lexical-analysis&#34;&gt;Lexical analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lexical analyzer is a part of the compiler front end and is responsible for tokenizing the given source file. What this means is that, when given a stream of characters, a lexical analyzer can turn that stream of characters into a set of distinct lexemes. These lexemes can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;be separated by some delimiter. A token can have many lexemes, which essentially means that a token is a category of lexemes if that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for example, following statement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt; if ( i == 0 )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;can be broken down into&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;lexemes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;token&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;if&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;condition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bracket_open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;i&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;indetifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;==&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;equal_sign&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bracket_end&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokenizing is very similar to how we break down complex sentences in natural languages. just like how a sentence is divided into different parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unlike humans, to achieve this task, lexical analyzers use pattern matching algorithms and regular expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also worth mentioning that lexical analysis or tokenizing can be done using unix utilities like FLEX and ANTLR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syntax-analysis&#34;&gt;Syntax analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntax analysis is the second phase of the compiler&amp;rsquo;s front end. Unlike lexical analysis, where pattern matching algorithms and regular expressions are used to identify tokens, Syntax analysis use a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;concept known as Context-Free Grammar (CFGs). Context-Free Grammar is kinda similar to regular grammar but it&amp;rsquo;s mainly used to describe the syntax of programming languages. basically, it&amp;rsquo;s a superset of regular grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the lexical analyzer outputs the stream of tokens, these tokens are then fed into the syntax analyzer. Then the syntax analyzer analyzes and parses the stream of tokens against different rules and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;detect syntax errors in the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for example, &lt;code&gt;if ( i == 0 &lt;/code&gt; is passed down, it is the syntax analyzers job to report it as an error. However, some syntax analyzers are capable of continuing the parsing process even if there are syntax errors. To achieve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this, syntax analyzers use error recovery strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After parsing all the syntax, the syntax analyzer should generate a parse tree. A parse tree is a representation of the production rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for example, applying left-derivation production rule on &lt;code&gt;x + b - c&lt;/code&gt;, resulting parse tree is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;E -&amp;gt; E - E

E -&amp;gt; E + E - E

E -&amp;gt; id + E - E

E -&amp;gt; id + id - id



        E
    ---------
    |   |   |
    E   -   E
____|____
|   |   |
E   +   E
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntax analysis can be done using YACC(Yet Another Compiler Compiler), CUP, Bison, and ANTLR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract-synstax-trees-asts&#34;&gt;Abstract Synstax Trees (ASTs)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like a parse tree, an abstract syntax tree or AST is a graph representation of the source code. How an AST differs from a parse tree is, an AST is a simplified version of the parse tree. And in ASTs operators are internal nodes. ASTs are also considered to be the out of syntax analysis phase of a compiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember CFGs?, in modern programming languages, there are lots of things that CFGs cant express. for example type definitions. Almost every modern language allows new types. However, CFGs cannot represent new types and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;their usage. ASTs can solve these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major usage of ASTs is that a full traversal of the AST data structure represents the correctness of the program. ASTs are heavily used in semantic analysis too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-end&#34;&gt;THE END&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah that&amp;rsquo;s it for the compiler front end. I suggest readers go through &amp;ldquo;Concepts of programming languages&amp;rdquo; for more detailed explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll do the optimization article soon. until then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, welcome to rxOred&#39;s corner of this inter-networked maze!</title>
      <link>https://rxOred.github.io/post/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 16:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rxOred.github.io/post/hello/</guid>
      <description>Tbh, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what to write here. A few years ago, when I started out programming, I never thought of or wanted to start blogging. Hell, I never wanted to get into security back then. But things change!.
Here I am, editing the first blog post :)
Anyway, about this blog. Here I will be posting my projects, research, guides, and other useless information on programming, system security, and reverse engineering.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Tbh, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what to write here. A few years ago, when I started out programming, I never thought of or wanted to start blogging. Hell, I never wanted to get into security back then. But things change!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I am, editing the first blog post :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, about this blog. Here I will be posting my projects, research, guides, and other useless information on programming, system security, and reverse engineering. I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to starting posting malware analysis reports and CTF writeups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I think that&amp;rsquo;s it :3&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
